WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Gracious Mama, it's not like you to
meet a train.
My dear, I'm taking you STRAIGHT to
the house.
We'll go back and change and return
for dinner.
~ Do you know what time she left
yesterday? ~ Not precisely.
The rest of us were at the
point-to-point.
~ We heard when we got back. ~ What are
we going to say now?
I've been awake the whole night.
There's only one thing we can say.
We have to tell Cora.
Well, isn't that rather a betrayal?
If anything happens to Edith and Cora
learns later
we knew all along, she would never
forgive us.
And I wouldn't blame her.
You see, as a mother, it is her
right.
But you don't plan to tell Robert?
~ He is Edith's father.
~ He's a man.
Men don't have rights.
They telephoned Lady Rosamund last
night. She's on her way here now.
It seems very hard they should have
guests staying
and more coming for dinner with this
going on.
They couldn't put them off without
telling them why.
It'll make for a funny evening.
~ We still don't know anything.
~ We know she's in London.
~ She bought a ticket for King's
Cross. ~ But where can she be hiding?
It seems a terrific imposition for
us to be here. Should we just leave?
Why? We've got Dicky Merton, the
Sinderbys and their son arriving.
~ We could put them off. ~ Please don't.
They're looking forward to it.
~ You are. ~ I don't think we should.
We have to give the impression Edith
has gone away to stay somewhere.
How terribly worrying this is for
you. I'm so sorry.
Why the song and dance? Edith's gone
away. So what?
We three should go for a walk and
leave them to talk.
Tony can be our guide. He must know
the gardens pretty well.
Maybe we should take some air.
I think we might emulate the others
~ and let Cora show us the garden. ~ I'm
not sure what good that'll do.
When I say we need some air, we need
some air. Cora.
If it's what you want. Mary, you can
manage the children when
they get here.
Of course.
There's a person downstairs, M'Lady.
A Mrs Drewe from Yew Tree Farm.
She's very anxious to see you.
Oh. Well, you'd better show her in
my sitting room.
I'm sorry, Mama. You go ahead
without me.
I can take you for a walk if you
like.
Why would I want to walk?
I'm going in to change. I'll sneak
upstairs so I don't disturb them.
~ See you at dinner. ~ Not if I see you
first.
I don't understand. You're so
well suited.
~ And you're much more relaxed with
her than you are with Mary. ~ Yes.
You must admit it's odd - Mary is
trying to break off
and Mabel is dying for love of you.
I know. But I can't break it off
with Mary. Not now.
Why not?
Well, I won't explain it but suffice
to say, it wouldn't be honourable.
You are an old dear if you think I
don't know what you're talking about.
~ But isn't it up to Mary?
~ It's not what she wants.
Not really. Did she look like a
woman today
trying to rid herself of a suitor?
You're muddling her instinct, which
is to hold every man in thrall,
and her wish, which is to break up.
~ I'm not convinced.
~ I wish you would be.
For everyone's sake.
~ Who was that letter from?
~ Mr Brook.
He's got a new job in Salford so he
doesn't want to renew the lease.
We need to find another tenant.
Damn it.
Don't be ungrateful. I've blessed
your mother every day
for leaving us the house. When you
have property, you have choices.
~ What should we do? ~ After he's gone,
let's ask for time off together.
Go down. See what condition he has
left it in then we can plan.
~ Why are you smiling?
~ Because whenever I see a problem,
you see only possibilities.
Did you both know?
Mrs Drewe told me Rosamund knew you
went to see the child with Edith.
~ Yes. ~ And you never thought to tell
me I have a third grandchild.
Edith didn't want me to.
~ It makes sense of that bewildering
trip to Switzerland. ~ What was
I to do?
~ She wouldn't get rid of it.
~ Get rid of it? ~ It was her idea.
But she wouldn't go through with it
in the end.
~ And what did you know? ~ Well, not
quite as much.
I knew why they were in Switzerland.
I thought she'd left the baby there.
That was the idea.
~ Edith didn't stick to it. ~ And you
never thought to involve me?
Her OWN mother. You, Rosamund, you
looked at that little girl
and you never thought it was my
business too?
Well, we wanted to contain it.
To make as little noise abroad as
possible.
So what changed? What tipped her
over the edge and into running away?
Well, I suppose we all knew Mr
Gregson was dead
but the confirmation must have been
very upsetting.
And Mrs Drewe was being difficult.
Clearly the child couldn't stay
there indefinitely.
So, we thought...
~ What did you think? ~ That it would be
better and safer
~ if the girl was sent abroad. ~ Now, we
have it.
Edith was told her child would be
taken away.
Are you going to say anything to
Robert?
No. I agree with one thing -
the secret is not ours to tell.
Somehow we must find Edith...
.. and we must hear from her what SHE
wants.
M'Lady.
~ I'm sorry to bother you. ~ What is it,
Mrs Hughes?
It may have slipped your mind,
M'Lady,
but do you remember I gave you a
train ticket
when we came to London for Lady
Rose's ball?
It was a return ticket that I found
in the pocket
~ of Mr Bates' overcoat.
~ Of course I remember.
I don't suppose you put it anywhere
for safekeeping?
~ Why? ~ Because we were wrong.
Far from proving Mr Bates went
to London on the day Mr Green died,
it proved he didn't. He bought the
ticket in York
but changed his mind and that's why
it was never given in.
So it was proof of his innocence not
his guilt?
That's about the size of it.
I'm afraid I burnt it, Mrs Hughes.
Atticus.
~ Hello. Lord and Lady Sinderby.
Hello. ~ Rose.
~ Oh, you know my cousin. ~ We were in
awe of your courage yesterday.
Well, courage or foolhardiness. Come
and see Mama and Papa.
To be honest, we're in the middle of
rather a drama.
~ Which I'll tell you about but you
mustn't let on. ~ Our first secret.
This is cold so it can go up now but
cover it till it's served.
~ Shall we work on Vanity Fair when
you've finished tonight? ~ I dunno.
Well, I'll ask you later.
Lord Merton's arrived so everyone is
here.
~ I'll announce it when you're ready.
~ I will be by the time you say it.
~ You're very glum. ~ Am I?
Don't tell me your enthusiasm for
learning is drying up.
Maybe. Have you read the papers
lately?
I wish I had the time!
Mr MacDonald seems to limp from
crisis to crisis.
They were going to do so much when
they came in.
The first Labour Government. Now, I
doubt they'll last the year.
~ Don't take it personally. ~ But I do.
When I think about it, it seems to
me that we're trapped.
Held fast in a system that gives us
no value and no freedom.
~ Oi. Speak for yourself! ~ I am. I do.
And now I'm wondering. Is it worth
it me trying to better myself?
What's the point?
That's it. They're coming in.
Miss Baxter.
I'm afraid you think I've got you
both into trouble.
~ I don't know what you mean. ~ Yes, you
do.
I said I had no proof. I gave them
nothing that would stand up.
~ Why did you have to say anything?
~ I was in a difficult position.
~ So now you've put us in one.
~ I'm very sorry. I am. Truly.
I have to clean some shoes.
~ Are you enjoying Yorkshire? ~ Well,
first, we and Yorkshire
~ have to get used to each other. ~ But
you haven't come up against
~ too many impassable barriers. ~ Lord
Grantham, we both know what
we're up against.
~ Happily, we're used to it. ~ You won't
have any trouble with us.
~ Lady Grantham's father was Jewish.
~ That isn't a guarantee of tolerance.
So it's a relief to hear you say it.
Atticus seems to be very taken with
your niece.
And I must say...
.. I find her quite
charming.
~ Does Lord Sinderby approve? ~ Well, you
know, he needs time
to settle into things.
Your mother never considered
converting.
I don't believe so.
Was it difficult? Having a different
religion from your father's?
Not that I recall.
Hm.
~ And you're not ashamed of him? ~ Lord
Sinderby, I would point out
that we never changed our name.
Hm. It was my grandfather's
decision.
I thought of changing it back but
the family felt they were English
now and they wanted to stay...
English.
Have you decided at last whether you
are leaving?
'At last' is the right phrase
but I want to make sure I do the
right thing.
I don't want to disrupt Sybbie's
life and then regret it.
You know they all want you to stay.
That only makes it more difficult.
Lord Grantham was saying Gregson
left Lady Edith his publishing
company.
~ Yes. ~ Then shouldn't someone
telephone the office?
Won't she go there? They must know
where to find her.
Of course. How clever you are.
Why? It seems rather obvious to me.
~ Your mother and Robert are hitting
it off. ~ She's not the problem. ~ Oh?
My father's the tough nut.
My people are the other way round.
My father's a darling
~ and my mother's the nut. ~ Then we
shall crack them against each other.
Strange how some people get married
and married and...
we can't manage it once.
Dogs barking in wrong trees spring to
mind.
Tony, I'm sorry if you feel
I'm tracking you round the country,
but I can't give up just yet.
We would be so happy if you'd let us.
And I won't be if I don't?
I remember my mother telling me, that
in the end,
happiness is a matter of choice.
Some people choose to be happy and
others select a course
that leads only to frustration and
disappointment.
~ And I'm one of the latter.
~ I terribly hope not.
For my sake.
I have a little announcement.
~ Are you sure? ~ I am.
You might like to know that Lord
Merton and I have decided
that we should get married.
How lovely.
Well, this calls for a toast.
I give you, Mrs Crawley.
Or should I say, the future Lady
Merton.
~ The future Lady Merton!
~ The future Lady Merton.
Naturally, it was the last thing I
ever thought would happen.
I forced her into it.
He wooed me into it and I'm terribly
pleased he did.
Well...
~ What's the matter, granny? ~ I was
worried about Edith.
I can't think why.
My dear, a lack of compassion can be
as vulgar
as an excess of tears.
Ah, Daisy. Have you decided?
Shall we discuss the vices of Miss
Becky Sharp?
I'm tired. I'm going up. Good night,
Mrs Patmore.
What's that about?
She had such hopes of the Labour
Government, she feels let down.
~ But she mustn't give up. ~ I don't
recall you being this keen
when Miss Bunting was teaching her.
I wouldn't interfere with
a professional but now she's gone,
I'd like to help if I can.
Sounds to me as if you've missed out
on your vocation.
Tell Daisy. Perhaps you can change
her mind.
~ She wouldn't listen to me.
~ Well spotted. What about Mr Mason?
Funnily enough, Mr Barrow might be
right for once.
~ How do we get him to speak to her?
~ Let me think on it.
I'm sorry if I seem distracted
but I'm truly so happy for you both.
I thought I'd give a dinner so she
could meet my sons.
~ Well, she has met Larry before.
~ Let's hope she's forgotten!
Why don't we do it here? We could
invite Granny and everyone.
You are my godfather and Isobel is
the grandmother of my child.
Oh, please let's. It seems only
right, Mama.
~ Of course. If you'd like. ~ Oh, that
would be very kind.
A signing of the bond between our
families.
I wish we didn't know the anguish
lurking around.
You love other people's secrets.
Not these days.
I can't tell you why I can't leave
Mary but...
~ you'd understand if I did.
~ Just promise me it's a struggle.
More than you know.
We must go but it's been such fun.
I hope you come to us next time.
We should love it. I suppose we just
have to wait and see what happens.
No need to hurry them into anything.
They're both very young.
Well, I would be delighted
if something were to come of it.
Good night, Lady Grantham. Lady
Rosamund.
The door, please, Molesley.
They're so easy in each other's
company. Anyone can see.
But he won't let me go.
Because you refuse to make it clear
that you want him to.
Just as he's moving off, you tug his
strings.
Send a clear message and he'll go.
I promise.
What is that message?
We'll think of something.
Atticus says the London office of
the magazine must know
how to get in touch with Edith.
~ I thought we weren't going to tell
anyone. ~ He's not anyone, is he?
Of course not. We could ring them
tomorrow but maybe I should go.
Mr Aldridge is leaving.
Oh.
~ I'll train up in the morning.
~ I'm coming with you. ~ I'm not going.
I'll have a horrible day worrying.
Trust me.
How can you imagine I'll ever trust
you again?
~ She doesn't mean it. ~ On the
contrary.
It's the most honest thing she's
ever said to me.
~ There you are.
~ Thank you.
Is our life overcomplicated?
~ In what way? ~ Mrs Patmore is buying a
house up here.
Why don't we sell the London house
and do the same?
We could rent it out as long as we
want to work out Downton.
~ And then live in it when we retire.
~ We had a dream once.
Of a small hotel in the area.
A London house, even a little one,
would buy something substantial here.
I hate to say his name...
.. but do you feel the whole business
of Mr Green might be over?
~ For us, I mean. ~ Well, they seem to
have accepted the fact
that I spent the day in York and
Miss Baxter has given them
~ nothing new to go on. ~ So we can dare
to plan our future again.
~ Like normal people. ~ Does that mean
what I hope it means?
Mr Bates, I thought you'd decided to
believe me
~ when I said that device was Lady
Mary's? ~ I do believe you.
~ I don't know why she wanted it but
I believe you. ~ Well, then...
You don't suppose there's anything
wrong with us, do you?
No.
I think it takes some people longer
than others.
That's all.
What would I do without you?
~ Did they get away? ~ Just about. The
train was late, thank heaven.
~ And it isn't going to be Tony?
~ I don't think so.
~ Nor Charles. ~ He decided that before
I did. ~ Well, well.
I don't suppose your ancient
father's opinion carries much weight.
'Fraid not. And I've just remembered
I said I'd go and see granny.
So, I don't think Tony is going to
be my next son-in-law.
I don't believe he is.
Pity. I'd have been so pleased but
there we are.
You're really not yourself, are you,
old girl?
And what about you? We don't want
you to be on your own forever.
Just to pick someone who shares the
family's values.
~ Someone who feels friendly towards
us is not the same thing. ~ No.
You're right. And I don't blame you
for the departure of Miss Bunting.
I didn't want to spend my life in a
bare knuckle fight.
But something's changed. I feel it.
I may as well tell you.
I've written to my cousin in Boston.
~ He's done well there and I'd like
his advice. ~ I see.
I apologise if my bad manners have
brought this on.
No need to apologise. I am what I am
and you are what you are.
~ Never the twain shall meet!
~ I wouldn't say that.
I do love you all, you know.
It'll be hard to go.
On both sides.
But we have no way of knowing
if Lady Edith will come in today.
It's already tea-time and we close
the office at six.
~ Then we'll wait until six. ~ And we'll
come back in the morning.
And every day till she either turns
up or contacts you with her
whereabouts.
It wouldn't be enough to give her
a message that you want to see her?
No, it would not be enough.
You've told her, haven't you?
You've broken your word.
~ No. I've... ~ Mrs Drewe came to the
house.
~ What did she want? ~ She felt you had
used her badly.
I confess it was a feeling we
shared.
~ I'm not coming back, you know. ~ Let's
not talk about it here.
~ Come to me for dinner. ~ No.
Very well, we'll discuss it now in
front of your new employees
and give them something to chew on.
There is a tea room at the end of
the street.
How are you, Spratt? Well, I hope.
~ Everyone has their troubles, M'Lady.
~ Oh, dear.
Spratt has been helping to train my
new maid. Denker.
I'd say she takes
after the dachshund, M'Lady.
~ In what way?
~ She's QUITE untrainable.
~ Spratt. ~ Will there be anything else,
Your Ladyship?
Sounds like trouble to me.
Are you certain Denker is worth it?
Oh, you must put dinner on Friday
into your diary.
That's when Dicky Merton is coming
with his sons.
Yes. I wonder if it is a good idea.
Isobel has got to meet them some
time.
And Larry won't make trouble for Tom
again. Not with Sybil dead.
Let us hope not.
Granny, I know why you're finding
this difficult.
~ Do you? ~ Yes, but you mustn't give in
to it.
~ What? Give in to what? ~ Isobel has
always been your protege.
She looks up to you and you have
kept her from harm in return.
Have I?
Yes. So of course it's difficult
that she is to take her place
~ among the leaders of the county.
~ Why?
~ Why is it difficult? ~ You needn't
pretend.
Your positions have changed - you
the widow in the Dower House,
Isobel a great lady presiding over a
great house.
But you simply have to be bigger
than that.
Is that what you think of me?
That I care about her change of
rank?
Well, you're not exactly pleased,
are you?
No. But that is not the reason.
Then what is?
If you must know...
.. I have got used to having a
companion.
A friend. You know, someone to talk
things over with.
~ Well, you'll still have us. ~ You have
your own lives.
And so you should.
But Isobel and I had a lot in
common.
And...
~ .. I shall miss her.
~ Granny,
you're quite dewy-eyed.
I never think of you as sentimental.
Nor am I.
You've made me regret my confidence.
Do have some cake.
And for your information...
I don't think Isobel has EVER looked
up to me.
Now, we drop the sticks in together
when I say.
Ready? Go!
Where are they?
~ There it is. ~ It's me! It's me!
~ Yes.
Now make a wish.
~ Darling, you know Aunt Edith has
gone to London? ~ Yes.
Well, I was thinking...
I wonder what if we were to leave
here and go and live
in a place far away across the sea?
~ What would you say?
~ Why?
Well, because...
~ .. it might be better for us to start
a new life there. ~ Why?
Because...
Because I hope to God I'm doing the
right thing.
That's the stable clock.
WE had better get back.
I've got an idea and I've told Mrs
Hughes but I want you to know it.
I could swear the train ticket
hadn't been used. I would swear it.
~ What? ~ I saw the ticket in Mrs Hughes'
hand when she found it in the coat.
It hadn't been torn in half. It was
whole. I saw it.
Did you? Indeed.
Things have moved on, Miss Baxter.
They know Mr Bates was in York on
that day.
I just wanted to be helpful.
We know how you like to be helpful,
Miss Baxter.
By talking to the police about us.
Excuse me, I couldn't help
overhearing.
Miss Baxter won't say it but she's
in a difficult position.
On the contrary, Miss Baxter keeps
saying it.
She says nothing else.
Mr Molesley, can you remove
the baize from the tables, please?
I'm ready to go up.
I'll come with you.
~ Ignore them. ~ I can't. I feel sorry
for them.
Then tell them why you had to talk
to the police.
I'd feel ashamed.
You're in luck. I'm only just back.
Listen carefully. Today, I learned
I've been posted on a trade
delegation to Poland.
~ I'll be gone for months. ~ Some people
have all the fun.
I want you to come up to London
tomorrow.
~ I've things I can't get out of
in the morning. ~ That doesn't matter.
~ I just need you from about seven
o'clock on. ~ What for?
Mabel's given me an idea of
how to settle it once and for all.
~ Just be here. ~ What sort of clothes?
Rags. We're going to the Kinema. Ring
me when you get to London.
Your wish is my command. Bye.
~ I'm worried about Isis.
~ Why? What's the matter with her?
She's not looking too clever. Did you
manage to get hold of Mr Stapeley?
I spoke to his wife, My Lord. He's
away until Friday.
~ Do you want me to try to find
someone else? ~ No.
~ I'll take her there myself on Friday
afternoon. ~ Has the gong been rung?
Just. Why do we bother to change?
It's you, me, Mary and Tom.
~ Don't let Aunt Violet hear you.
~ Where have you been?
I went to have tea with Atticus. We
met halfway in Ripon.
~ It's getting quite serious then?
~ Fingers crossed.
~ But darling, you don't want to rush
into anything. ~ Oh, but I do.
I want to rush in like billy-o.
Rose, it's a big thing you're
contemplating.
Bigger still because of the
circumstances.
~ You sound like Lord Sinderby. ~ I can
see he wasn't keen.
He doesn't want Atticus to marry out
of the faith. He minds.
Why shouldn't he mind? He's an
important figure in that community.
~ But you're not against it, are you?
~ Of course not.
~ Still, I think you ought to write to
your parents. ~ Daddy won't stop me.
~ I don't believe he will. ~ And Mummy
hates everyone so what's the
difference?
Even so, it's best not to pretend
it'll be plain sailing.
~ Where's Marigold Now?
~ The hotel arranges a baby-
sitter when you need one.
~ May I see her?
~ I don't think so.
~ Not tonight.
~ So what are you going to do?
I was toying for a while with the
idea of going to America.
~ Oh, don't be ridiculous.
~ Why is it ridiculous? She's
half American. Isn't she?
I thought I'd drop my title and
invent a dead husband.
Then I'd be Mrs Thing
in Detroit or Chicago.
~ Where I wouldn't run into anyone
I knew. ~ So, is that your plan?
I don't want the magazine business
to fall into ruin.
How could I keep an eye on it
overseas?
~ And I would like Marigold to grow up
English. ~ What is the alternative?
~ An invented dead husband here? ~ I'd
never get away with it in London.
I thought I'd make her my orphaned
godchild.
Well, I have a different plan.
~ I'd like you to bring her home.
~ No.
I won't be the county failure. Poor
demented Lady Edith
who lost her virtue and her reason.
Just listen to my plan.
The Drewes would reach a reluctant
conclusion
that they can't afford to raise
their friend's child.
You've grown so fond of the girl,
you ask if she might join
~ the others in the Downton nursery.
~ The Drewe plan was mad enough.
But this is COMPLETELY ludicrous.
~ How could it possibly work?
~ Papa must never know the truth.
I've thought about it and don't
agree.
It would take time for him to get
used to the idea, he would make it.
~ He'd never look at me in the same
way again. ~ Very well.
~ If that's how you feel, he doesn't
have to know. ~ Nor Mary.
I couldn't have her queening
it over me.
No-one has to know who doesn't know
- your grandmother, Rosamund,
you and me.
Everyone else will be told the
story.
And how would we execute this
insanity?
A farmer's foster child turns up in
the Downton nursery?
People adopt babies all the time
from all kinds of backgrounds.
~ So you're going to do this?
~ I'll telephone Mr Drewe tonight
when we get back to Belgrave Square
and I'll ask for his help.
~ And what about his wife?
~ Let him manage her.
Edith and I will go home tomorrow.
I'll ask Mr Drewe to meet the train
and take Marigold, then
we'll discuss the Drewes' situation.
At last, Edith will fetch the girl
and bring her back in broad daylight.
Time to call it a day, ladies.
I couldn't agree more.
And one for you, Mr Moseley.
I'm going out with Lady Mary this
afternoon but only for the night.
~ You didn't have much warning. ~ I know.
Something has come up.
~ I suppose there's no point in you
looking in on the house. ~ Not now.
Leave it till Mr Brook's left and we
can both go.
~ Ooh, it's an invitation from Mr
Mason. ~ What? My Mr Mason?
Your Mr Mason. He wants us to come
to the farm tomorrow for luncheon.
If we can get the time off.
Why don't you go with them? I'm sure
Her Ladyship wouldn't mind.
~ What is it to you? ~ You did me a good
turn when I'd done you a bad one.
~ So I think you deserve a treat. ~ He's
right. It'll do you good.
But I've not been asked.
Mr Mason would be glad to see you
but would Mr Carson let us go?
Ooh, I think he will if you allow me
to handle it.
He won't like it when we've got a
big dinner on.
Just let me tell him. I'm the one
with the extra work.
Would Miss Baxter be able to come
with us? As Mr Barrow says.
Well, I don't see why not as long as
you're back in time. You
can go early.
I still don't understand why he'd
write to Mr Moseley.
I might have mentioned he's been
helping you with your books.
I write to him now and then.
~ Can you see him? ~ Not yet.
Oh, my God. There's Mary.
~ What? ~ There's Mr Drewe. What shall
we do? ~ Leave it to me.
Mr Drewe. Can you help my mother
with her suitcases?
My sister Mary is on the platform.
Go to the next station
and come back.
I'll cover the cost.
Come on you. That's it. Come on,
darling. It's just a game.
~ So, you found her. ~ I did.
I don't know what the fuss was
about. I wanted a day or
two in London.
I knew it. I said that's all it was.
What a nonsense they made.
~ Why are you here? ~ I'm catching the
first train to London. It's due
any minute.
~ When will you be back? ~ I'm not sure.
Tomorrow, I think.
Don't forget the dinner on Friday.
We have a duty to protect Isobel
from Larry Grey.
I don't think he'll try anything,
do you?
~ Well, have a lovely time. ~ I'm sure I
will.
That was close.
Have I met your younger son? I
remember the elder one.
I should think you do.
After his outburst the last time.
But Larry was fond of Sybil and not
about to welcome the man
who'd won her.
Let us hope the years since have made
him more forgiving.
I'm looking forward to it and think
we should make no reference
~ to the earlier meeting. ~ How lucky I
am in you.
~ I know it every time you speak.
~ Flatterer.
I should be going. I'll see you on
Friday. I can't wait.
~ Thank you so much for my lovely tea.
~ Not a bit.
Spratt will see you out.
Spratt still looks rather down in
the mouth.
I'm afraid the battles with Denker
are far from resolved.
It's good to have a moment alone to
say how much I appreciate
your kindness to Dicky. I know you
don't approve.
~ Which makes you all the more
generous. ~ It's too late to stop it.
How is Prince Kuragin?
I haven't heard from him lately. Why?
I was wondering how you were going
to manage when the Princess arrives.
~ Will you receive her here? ~ Well, I'm
not sure.
Since Shrimpie hasn't found her yet,
I've got time to plan.
~ Ah.
~ Oh!
What is it now, Spratt?
I'm sorry to bother Your Ladyship.
Especially when you have company.
I'm afraid I must...
hand in my notice.
I have suffered as much as anyone
can expect to suffer
in the course of their duties.
I can take no more, M'Lady.
I can take no more.
Typical Spratt.
He's as touchy as a beauty losing her
looks.
~ You don't think he meant it? ~ If he
did, he'd have given it quietly.
For a good reference in return. No.
No.
~ It's a demonstration of discontent.
~ So you'll forgive his outburst?
Anything rather than find a new
butler.
~ Why did we have to rush out? ~ Come
and stand here.
~ I still don't understand. ~ You will.
Do exactly as I tell you and you
will. Kiss me.
~ What? ~ Kiss me. Now!
Mary.
~ What are you doing here? ~ So what did
you think of the film?
There was no need to stage a
tableau.
If you'd just told me I was allowed
to walk away, I'd have gone.
~ Without any silly games. ~ But I DID
tell you. Often.
~ And you didn't go. ~ Well, I'm going
now.
I know. And I wish you both such
happiness, Tony.
~ I do. ~ I don't want to hurry anyone
but can we bring this to an end?
I've had quite enough sentiment from
John Barrymore and I'm starving.
Goodbye, Mary. And good luck to you.
I'm glad to have engineered a
resolution
~ even if I should have thought of it
long ago. ~ He said we didn't need to.
But I know we did. It's funny. I
feel quite sad in a way.
But not sad enough to change my
mind.
~ She's nice, you know. She'll suit him
very well. ~ Good. I'm glad.
So, what now? Shall
we find ourselves some dinner too?
Let's. We'll toast the fun we've had.
And whatever the future may bring
us.
~ When are you off to Poland? ~ I catch
the boat train on Monday.
So I'm scrambling around trying to
get everything done.
~ When are you back? ~ Oh, not for
months or even a year.
You'll be married by then.
There. Are we all finished?
How lovely, Daisy, to have such a
beautiful place to come to.
~ She's always welcome is Daisy. ~ I've
not been here enough lately.
You've been busy I know. With your
books.
~ That takes up time. ~ I think I'll
stop it now.
So I'll be able to visit more.
~ Do you think she's right to give up
her studies, Mr Mason? ~ I do NOT.
~ Don't you want to see more of me?
~ You know I do.
But education is power. Don't forget
that.
There's no limit to what you can
achieve
~ if you'll just give a year or two to
mastering those books. ~ I agree.
There are millions out there who
could have done so much
if they'd only been given an
education.
I'm one of 'em. I could have made
something worthwhile of my life
~ if I'd had the chance. ~ Don't talk as
if your life were not worthwhile...
~ when I know it is. ~ I think
the system is slanted against us.
The men in charge will always be the
men in charge.
How can you say that with a Labour
Government in power?
~ I doubt they'll last the year. ~ Next
time, when they're elected,
it'll be for longer, and soon
a Labour Government might seem
ordinary.
~ Do you think I should stick at it?
~ I do!
And now, we ought to think
about getting you back to the bus.
~ Let me take these. ~ No. No.
Daisy and I are your hosts.
~ Thank you. ~ Well, thank you.
He's made a daughter out
of his widowed daughter-in-law.
I like it when good things come from
bad.
Have you thought of explaining to
Mr Bates why you had to speak out?
He'd understand if anyone would.
He's troubles enough
without burdening him with mine.
We should go. We must be back in
good time for Mrs Crawley's dinner.
Mr Carson says there was trouble
the last time
~ Lord Merton's elder son came to
Downton. ~ What happened?
Alfred told me if Mr Branson hadn't
been too drunk to stand
we'd have had fisticuffs on the
table.
And here's my thinking life
in a great house must be dull work.
Walk on.
Do Mr and Mrs Drewe really want you
to take her?
Or is it just a way of keeping her
here till they have her back?
I don't think so. They simply can't
afford another child.
~ And there aren't any prior claims?
~ Apparently not.
That's why they took her in the
first place.
What did he say? Is she carrying
puppies? Because -
~ I don't see how that could have
happened. ~ No.. It's not that.
She's got cancer. Poor old thing.
Oh, no. Oh, how I hate that word.
He said it won't take long now.
He offered to put her down there and
then but I couldn't let him.
Oh, Papa. I'm so, so sorry.
Of course, it was stupid to mind so
much.
She doesn't even know who I am beyond
the hand that feeds her
but even so...
We'll keep her right here. This is
her spot.
She'll know she's back at home.
I suppose we can't stop this ghastly
dinner tonight.
I don't see how. Dicky's sons have
come from London.
~ And Atticus was on the same train.
~ No, of course we can't put it off.
~ I wasn't thinking. ~ Why don't we say
that you're ill?
~ I could watch her. I don't have to
go to the dinner. ~ I think you do.
To lay the ghost of the last time
Larry Grey was here.
I asked them to bring them down
early.
~ Hello, Daddy. ~ Come to Mama, darling.
Hello, my darling.
So, how should I answer?
~ What's this about? ~ The child at the
Drewe's house.
Oh. It seems idiotic to me.
And me. What about if you want to
start a family of your own?
But I dote on her. If they send her
to some horrid orphanage,
~ I'd never forgive myself. ~ Can't you
just give them some money?
~ So they can keep her.
~ I think...
.. Mrs Drewe finds it too much. It
isn't only the money.
~ It seems a bit feeble. ~ Does it?
Looking at these two.
So, should I take her?
Papa?
~ I'll leave it to your mother.
~ Well...
I believe we should offer little
Marigold a home here.
Do you really, darling?
Well, then, I suppose that's
settled.
Have all the guests arrived?
~ I think so. ~ I should tell
Mrs Patmore it won't be long now.
What are these?
Mr Carson's got a notion he and I
might buy a place
as an investment and maybe run it as
a guesthouse or rent it out.
How strange.
Mr Bates was talking about doing
something similar.
I suppose we're all beginning
to think of a different future
whether we want to or not.
The other day, Mr Drewe was on the
platform.
When Lady Mary and I were waiting
for the London train.
~ Oh, yes. ~ Then her Ladyship and Lady
Edith arrived.
And he got into their carriage. He
helped lift their bags out.
~ But then he just stayed there.
~ In first class?
That'll have cost him a pretty
penny.
When the train moved off, I thought
for a moment he had a child
on his lap.
~ I may have been wrong. ~ Anna, you
shouldn't involve yourself
in any speculation of that sort.
The child is safe and the child is
loved.
And that's all we need to be sure
of.
I've been hearing about Edith's
plan. How marvellous of her.
If you ask me, it's absolutely
crackers.
~ Cora seems pleased. ~ What idea is
this?
Edith has taken in a motherless
child and is giving her
a home here.
I should have thought an orphan an
uncomfortable piece of baggage
for an unmarried woman.
You mean a man might not want
to take the child on?
Well, I wouldn't.
~ Rose, have you written to your mother
about Mr Aldridge? ~ I have now.
~ And will she approve? ~ Don't be
disappointing, Aunt Violet, please.
I promise you we know difference in
religion is a big thing.
~ Quite right. How would you bring up
any children, for example? ~ Children?
~ When did this happen? ~ Talking
hypothetically.
The fact is, most marriages that
fail,
founder for precisely this kind of
reason.
~ An irreconcilable difference.
~ Or maybe they just don't get on.
No, I'd agree with Larry.
It's usually more than that.
It might be different beliefs, or
different nationalities
or a huge age gap.
It the end, they cannot see
eye-to-eye.
~ I don't see what you're getting at.
~ You mean to marry Mrs Crawley.
She seems very nice and I wish you
both every happiness.
Thank you.
But that doesn't prevent me from
seeing the wide disparity in class
and background may prove your
undoing.
~ What did you say? ~ Only that Mrs
Crawley, a decent middle class woman
with neither birth nor fortune
is expecting to fill another's shoes
as one of the leaders of the county.
Is she capable of it?
Or will her inevitable failure prove
a source of misery to them both?
Do you know Mrs Crawley's late son
was my heir?
What does that prove? Everyone has
distant cousins who are odd.
How dare you?! Will you GO, Larry?
I had to make excuses for your
rudeness the last time
you sat at this table. It is tiring
to think I should be called upon
~ to do so AGAIN. ~ I know the choice of
in-laws is eccentric.
In this family, you already boast a
chauffeur and soon you can
claim a Jew -
Why don't you just get out, you
bastard?!
And suddenly we've slipped into a
foreign tongue.
Well, if that is how you feel?
I do not endorse Tom's language but
that is certainly how we all feel.
Then, Lady Grantham, goodbye.
And thank you for a delightful
evening.
What did you imagine?
That we would welcome you with open
arms?
~ He actually called him that? ~ He did.
Right to his face.
~ Mr Moseley, please.
~ I think he was right to say it.
He may have been right but I will
not have bad language in
front of the maids.
I feel sorry for Mrs Crawley. Why
should she be humiliated?
~ They're leaving early.
~ No wonder.
Mr Moseley, why are you
down here? Not gossiping I hope?
Oh, no, no, Mr Carson, no.
Golly, what an evening.
~ We won't forget it in a hurry. ~ Let
us remember it for two reasons.
~ One bad, one good. ~ What's the good
one? ~ I hope it is good.
~ I'm listening. ~ See, the thing is, it
occurs to me
~ that we're already having to defend
ourselves. ~ Yes.
Let's have a real reason to.
That is, if you feel equal to it.
I'm not going to give you an answer
until you say it properly.
~ Do I have to kneel down?
~ Of course.
But you don't have to stay kneeling
for very long.
Rose, darling Rose...
.. will you marry me?
~ Oh, you can get up now. ~ Come on.
We ought to be serious. The truth is
we haven't known each other long.
~ And they're right. There are bound
to be problems. ~ The way I see it,
we both know we're going to get
married in the end.
~ We know we're right together.
~ Yes!
~ I suppose we do.
~ That's all I need to hear.
I'll telephone tomorrow
~ and we'll settle who tells what
to whom and when. ~ Oh, darling.
I'm going to wait in the car. Take
as long as you like.
~ We'll laugh about this one day.
~ The sooner, the better.
~ Night. ~ Good night.
~ Tell me it won't change your mind.
~ I can't talk about this tonight,
nor for some time to come.
And I think Rose and her young man
will take up
every scrap of attention we have for
weddings.
~ Please don't say that.
~ Papa!
Larry's been in the car since he
left the dining room.
~ I'm just coming. ~ I'll say good
night, Mrs Crawley.
Good night.
Don't blame Larry. He was close to
his mother
and hates the thought
of a replacement. They both do.
You don't need to remind me.
The boys take after their mother in
every possible way.
I'm going to sleep in the dressing
room tonight.
I'm not cross. I just want to have
her with me.
Stay here.
The thing is, I'm pretty sure she
won't last till morning
and I don't want her to be
frightened.
Then lay her here between us.
And she'll know she has someone who
loves her very much next to her.
Two people who love her and each
other very much on either side.
I only hope I can say the same when
my time comes.
Love may not conquer all but it can
conquer quite a lot.
~ Mummy, Daddy, can you try to behave
like a happy couple? ~ Wouldn't that
be dishonest?
~ I could get a job in London, I know
I could. ~ I'm sure you could.
We have our memories, you and I.
I feel as if our household is
breaking up, Carson.
He's trying to bully it out but it's
best not to stand in his way.